http://www.tourdafrique.com/privacy-policy

OUR HISTORY
WHY TDA?
OUR HISTORY
WHY TDA?
Our History
Why TDA?
Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy was last updated on October 22, 2018.
1. Introduction
1.1 In this policy, “we”, “us”, “TDA” and “our” refer to Tour d’Afrique Ltd. (carrying on business as TDA Global Cycling). For more information about us, see Section 12.
1.2 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our clients and website visitors.
1.3 We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.
1.4 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our clients and website visitors; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.
1.5 We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.
2. How we use your personal data
2.1 In this Section 2 we have set out:
a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;
b) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
c) the legal bases of the processing.
2.2 We may process data about your use of our website and services (“usage data”). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. This data is anonymized and not linked to your personal identity. The source of the usage data is Google Analytics. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.
2.3 We may process your account data (“account data”). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.4 We may process your information included in your personal profile on our website (“profile data”). The profile data may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, interests and hobbies. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at you request, to enter into such a contract.
2.5 We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services (“enquiry data”). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.6 We may process information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information (“customer relationship data”). The customer relationship data may include your name, your contact details, and information contained in communications between us and you. The source of the customer relationship data is you. The customer relationship data may be processed for the purposes of managing our relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of those communications and promoting our products and services to customers. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper management of our customer relationships.
2.7 We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website (“transaction data”). The transaction data may include your contact details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.
2.8 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“notification data”). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.9 We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data”). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.
2.10 We may process data necessary for the provision of travel services (“travel data”). This data may include your passport scan, passport photo scan, passport details, travel insurance policy information, health information and personal data necessary for travel documents and visas. The source of this data is you. This data may be processed for the provision of travel services, operating our website, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.11 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.
2.12 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.
2.13 In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
2.14 Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.
3. Data security
3.1 We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.
3.2 We restrict access to personal information to TDA employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.
4. Providing your personal data to others
4.1 We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
4.2 We may disclose usage data, account data, profile data, enquiry data, customer relationship data, transaction data, notification data, correspondence data and travel data to our suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the provision of travel services, operating our website, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.
4.3 Financial transactions relating to our website and services may be handled by our payment services providers, PayPal and Square. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at https://www.paypal.com/ca/webapps/mpp/ua/legalhub-full?locale.x=en_CA and https://squareup.com/ca/legal/privacy
4.4 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
4.5 If TDA becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.
5. International transfers of your personal data
5.1 In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside of Canada.
5.2 Our offices are located in Canada. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of this country.
5.3 The hosting facilities for our website are situated in the United States. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of this country. Transfers to this country will be protected by appropriate safeguards.
5.4 Subcontractors of usage data, account data, profile data, enquiry data, customer relationship data, transaction data, notification data, correspondence data and travel data, are situated in Canada and the United States. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards.
5.5 You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.
6. Retaining and deleting personal data
6.1 This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.
6.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.
6.3 In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, the period of retention of usage data, account data, profile data, enquiry data, customer relationship data, transaction data, notification data, correspondence data and travel data may be determined based on your continued use of or interest in our products and services.
6.4 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
7. Amendments
7.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
7.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.
8. Your rights
8.1 In this Section 8, we have summarized the rights that you have under data protection law, including under Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.
8.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:
a) the right to access;
b) the right to rectification;
c) the right to erasure;
d) the right to restrict processing;
e) the right to object to processing;
f) the right to data portability;
g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
h) the right to withdraw consent.
8.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.
8.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.
8.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
8.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.
8.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
8.8 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:
a) consent; or
b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,
and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
8.9 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the state of your habitual residence or the place of the alleged infringement.
8.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
8.11 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us.
9. About cookies
9.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
9.2 Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
9.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
9.4 By clicking “Accept”, you agree to our use of cookies and those of our service providers. You may refuse cookies by disabling them in your browser.
10. Cookies that we use
10.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:
a) authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;
b) status – we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website;
c) security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally;
d) analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services; and
e) cookie consent – we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally.
11. Cookies used by our service providers
11.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.
11.2 We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
11.3 We use Olark to provide instant chat services on our website. This service uses cookies to identify you and facilitate the chat process. You can view the privacy policy of this service provider at https://www.olark.com/privacy-policy.
12. Our details
12.1 This website is owned and operated by Tour d’Afrique Ltd. (c.o.b as TDA Global Cycling).
12.2 Our principal place of business is at 205-1179 King Street West, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, M6K 3C5.
12.3 You can contact us:
a) by mail, to the postal address given above;
b) our website contact form;
c) by telephone, at the contact number published on our website; or
d) by email, using the email address published on our website.
LATEST NEWS
How Far Can I Cycle in a Day? 10 Things to Consider
SPOILER ALERT: The answer is that you can probably cycle 100 km in a day. On a supported cycling…
UPDATED October 8, 2020 BY The TDA Team
The Pub Ride: A Literary Journey
At the end of a beautiful day on the Pub Ride Cycling Tour, the cyclists can head to one…
UPDATED October 6, 2020 BY Michael Coo
Health & Medical Preparation for a Long Distance Cycling Tour
You might have tuned up your bike and gotten advice on what to pack, but have you thought about…
UPDATED October 1, 2020 BY The TDA Team
REGISTER NOW!
TDA GLOBAL CYCLING
Our History
Contact
Terms of Use
Privacy Policy
© 2020 TDA Global Cycling
Facebook
Instagram
Reset
All tours are priced in either USD or EUR. This tool will show you the current equivalent cost in your own currency. Please note that if paying in a different currency, payment must be made using the official daily exchange rate at time of payment.
Questions? Feedback? powered by Olark live chat software
COVID-19: WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW
Sign up for our monthly newsletter and
Get free access to 101 tips
101 Tips for First Time Cycle Tourists
Submit
Thank you for signing up for our monthly newsletter
An email has been sent to you. Kindly click on the link to confirm your email address and we will immediately share our 101 Tips wth you.
Questions? Feedback? powered by Olark live chat software
